[Forging Justice]
[Episode 29]
Why didn't you go home?
Go home?
What home? I don't have a home.
Have you been drinking?
I went out to eat with some friends
and had a sip.
What have you been up to?
I reorganized
some files.
And went over some
old cases
to learn from them.
You just can't sit still, can you?
My wife went to Beijing,
for a foreign company.
She might not come back.
Isn't that funny?
I was the one
who always wanted to go to Beijing.
And in the end, she went.
What about your daughter?
She's at home, doing fine.
At a time like this,
a daughter needs her dad the most.
Here.
Have some water, take a moment,
then go home and be with your kid.
Can we talk a bit more?
I don't mean anything else.
I'm feeling really down.
Just need someone to talk to.
In Binjiang, you're the only one
I can open up to.
Yizhong and Lu are in Binjiang too.
Can't you open up
to them?
You three
were close back in school.
Yu, you've actually
had a lot in life.
But you never look at
what's right in front of you.
You keep moving forward
and losing things along the way.
Is it worth it?
Go home.
Turn off the light for me, will you?
It's really hard to find any new
evidence in this case now.
From what you see so far,
first,
no blood on the murder weapon.
Second,
the wound isn't unique to that weapon.
Even the blood
on Hu Xudong's shirt
might not be Yin Ping's.
You don't even trust
the forensic report?
That's not a definitive result.
It's just an expert opinion.
And with the current
blood typing technology,
even in the UK,
the error rate
would be 20%.
So you're convinced
this case falls into
that 20%?
What makes you so sure?
Are we in the UK?
No, well,
in Hu Xudong's confession,
he mentioned that the three buttons
fell off
during the struggle with Yin Ping,
and he picked them up after the murder.
We went to the scene yesterday.
We did an experiment after dark.
It's pitch black there after dark,
you can't see anything.
Let alone three buttons,
even if you threw three pancakes,
I wouldn't be able to find them.
Maybe he had a flashlight.
None of the records,
including Hu Xudong's own confession,
mention a flashlight.
Then let's wait.
Wait for
the supplementary investigation results.
Anyway, based on the current evidence,
we don't have any solid evidence
to prove
that Hu Xudong killed him.
You know that too.
What are you trying to say?
I'm saying,
is it possible that the procuratorate
might withdraw the prosecution?
There's an Arabian folktale collection
called "One Thousand and One Nights",
also known as "Arabian Nights".
Yizhong, you're too idealistic.
What do you mean?
Did you send Yang?
Where?
To Jiangbei to investigate Jia Peng.
Yes.
Zhang Hongshan, get up.
Are you blind?
Didn't you see my clothes here?
I'm going to my daughter's
parent-teacher meeting later.
Geez.
Jiang Bin.
Your mentor has gone crazy.
Don't let him lead you astray.
Show some respect.
Call me Chief.
Chief Jiang,
if you side with outsiders,
your authority will be affected.
If the higher-ups find out
you've been digging on your own,
you'll have to
face the consequences.
Did I say
I was reopening the investigation?
Just looking into Jia Peng's information
is perfectly legal and aboveboard.
What's wrong with that?
What have you found out?
Jia Peng should have
been executed long ago.
Why hasn't it been carried out?
Well, Jia Peng
appealed as soon as
he was sentenced to death.
After the review,
he said
he had major case details to confess.
He said
he not only killed those three girls,
but also robbed a taxi.
So that meant
a retrial and more investigation.
And now I hear
he's going to report his cellmates'
other crimes.
With all this back and forth,
it's been dragged out until now.
Right now
he's just living one more day
at a time.
Then what about Yan Jicai's case?
You finally figured it out?
If he really did it,
he'll confess
sooner or later to stay alive.
And when that happens,
we'll be on the back foot.
Hey, Big Bottle.
What's on your mind?
Still thinking about
that Prosecutor Zhang?
Big Bottle,
let's be realistic.
She's married now, living her own life.
Goes home after work,
gets into bed with her husband.
You think she's got time for you?
Even if they let you out first,
do you think your wife would wait?
Yeah.
She probably remarried long ago.
She couldn't hold out.
Right?
What's with you?
Why are you hitting people?
What are you doing?
Stop it!
Stop fighting!
Squat down!
Everyone, step back!
Squat down! Hands on your head!
Stop fighting!
Yan Jicai, let go!
Squat down!
Everyone, squat down!
Yan Jicai.
You've only behaved for a few days.
Why are you acting up again?
What's wrong with you?
Do you want a longer sentence?
I want to see Prosecutor Guo.
You want to see Prosecutor Guo
for everything.
What if Prosecutor Guo
is no longer here?
Are you going to stop living?
Say that again.
Guard Sun.
I haven't seen Prosecutor Guo
for a long time.
Guard Sun, be honest with me.
Has he given up on me?
He's fine.
He just went on an urgent business trip.
Before he left,
he specifically told me
to have you behave
and not cause any trouble.
That's the only way
you won't let him down.
That last part was from me.
Think it over yourself.
Hello?
This is the Prosecutor's Office
at Bieshan Prison.
Who is looking for Prosecutor Guo?
I am.
I'm Zhang Lihui.
Please wait a moment.
Ms. Liu,
someone named Zhang Lihui
is calling for Mr. Guo.
Give it to me.
Lihui, right?
Yes, it's me.
It's Liu Wei.
Ms. Liu,
where is my mentor?
He's on a business trip.
A long one.
Somewhere down south, I think.
Not sure if it's Guangzhou
or Shenzhen.
He didn't specify.
He won't be back for two or three months.
Why didn't he
tell me?
Ms. Liu,
do you have his number there?
I really don't.
Okay, I see.
Thank you, Ms. Liu.
Ms. Liu,
what day is Mr. Guo having surgery?
Today.
[Inpatient Department]
Hold on.
Guo,
don't be afraid.
Don't worry.
We'll all be waiting right outside.
It'll go well.
It will.
I'm not afraid.
I'm just worried Lihui
will come looking for me.
What will you do?
Y-You repeat it.
I'll hold it in.
I won't say a word.
And you?
I'll remind the prison again.
Make sure they don't tell Yan Jicai.
Wait,
did you actually remind them?
Don't you trust me?
I'm just worried.
Just shut up. Shut up.
At a time like this,
you're still thinking about an inmate.
I'm afraid he might do something stupid.
He takes things too hard.
If he finds out I have cancer,
he'll—
Please stop talking. It's time to go in.
Guo.
Please wait here.
It's fine.
Mentor, where did you
go on your business trip?
I couldn't reach you.
Worried. Please reply.
Captain Lyu.
You're here.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Here, have some tea.
How is Siyi recovering?
Good. She's recovering well.
The doctor said it's very optimistic.
Thank you.
Thank you for always caring about her.
It's the least I could do.
You don't want to do gymnastics.
I totally get it.
My dream was to be a lawyer.
I even went to law school for it.
And then what?
As soon as I graduated,
my dad refused to let me be a lawyer.
Why?
He didn't want me to repeat his mistakes.
He meant well,
but it's also pretty sad.
By the way,
you didn't become a lawyer,
so what do you do?
I'm a journalist.
So
you didn't come here to skip stones?
No.
Your mom even threw ketchup at me.
That was you?
Yeah, it was me.
Just leave.
I don't want to lie to you,
but I really wasn't
scheming—
Go away!
There's one thing I'd like to ask you.
You see,
my daughter Lyu Siyi
chose to kill herself
to prove her innocence.
Does that mean
Wang Danni was lying?
To be honest,
and don't take this the wrong way,
without witnesses,
it's a Rashomon situation.
Anything is possible.
That's exactly what I want to hear.
By that logic,
even if Yan Jicai killed himself
in prison,
that wouldn't prove
his innocence either,
right?
Captain Lyu,
that's different.
How is it different?
Just hearing him cry foul,
we wouldn't easily believe it.
A lot of evidence shows
that Yan Jicai is not the killer.
Let me put it the other way,
the current evidence
cannot prove
that Yan Jicai is the killer.
Then let me ask you this,
if
either Wang Danni
or my daughter
Lyu Siyi must be lying,
who do you think is more likely?
I think your assumption
is wrong.
How is it wrong?
One of them must be lying?
Why can't both of them
be telling the truth?
How is that possible?
Maybe they mis-saw,
misremembered,
or misjudged.
Maybe it was all a misunderstanding.
Then that misunderstanding would have
cost far too much.
As for Yan Jicai's case,
I've been reflecting on myself lately.
Have I been
too stubborn
and too subjective?
But there is one thing
I have never wavered on.
We
should do our best
to give this case,
give Yan Jicai,
and give the law
a fair chance,
to fight for a
retrial that can convince
our own conscience.
As for the result,
that matters less, actually.
Prosecutor Zhang,
I've done my best
on this case.
What I can do now is very limited.
But at the same time, I want to say,
it's been an honor to know you.
I've learned
a lot from you.
Thank you.
Captain Lyu.
I've already paid for the tea.
Goodbye.
This is our search warrant.
Let me see that.
What are you doing with this crappy glove?
I'll call the police station.
Captain Wang, we found it.
Put this on.
Which hand?
Left hand.
Take a picture.
These two aren't a pair.
Just put them on.
Take a picture.
If you ask me,
just this pair of gloves
is enough to press charges.
Lin.
Are you still insisting
on another supplementary investigation?
Lu.
Lu!
What?
Come here.
Geez.
What do you want?
Put that down.
Wait—
Put that down, will you?
Ow, ow, ow.
Ow.
Why are you poking me?
See it now?
I see it. You've lost your mind.
What do you mean?
See it or not?
Left hand.
I poked you with my left hand.
Look, all your "wounds"
are concentrated
on the right side of your abdomen,
right?
Yin Ping's were the same.
Alright.
[Registration Office]
Hello, I'm his son.
This is Prosecutor Chen—
no,
Lawyer Chen.
Dad.
Prosecutor Chen has been
helping our family these past few years.
He also helped me a lot
with my college entrance exam.
Qiao Wu
and Lame Zheng...
Executed.
They were executed half a year ago.
You and your mentor sent them away?
I'm no longer at the procuratorate.
I'm a lawyer now.
They're both dead?
Should I thank you for that?
If I were still out there,
there'd be a third one.
You didn't come see me
because you missed me, did you?
I need your help. Take a look at this.
Who's this?
Don't worry about who it is.
Just treat him as the victim.
The real victim
was a little thinner than him,
and
a little shorter.
Can you tell anything?
The killer
is left-handed.
Left-handed.
An expert with a knife.
In your words, a habitual offender.
How can you tell?
Well,
a rookie would stab wildly when panicked.
This guy
avoided the bones with every stab.
Could he stab like this in the dark?
I could.
Well,
welcome back next time.
Let me talk to my son.
Right.
Come on, talk to your dad.
Are your studies going well?
P-Pretty good.
Mr. Chen.
Was my dad really called the Knife King?
I only know your dad's surname is Wang.
I've always heard people say
he's a legend in Binjiang.
That's no legend.
Your dad committed intentional assault
and was sentenced to life.
There were seven victims in total.
Two were severely injured,
and one was permanently disabled.
My dad also told me to tell you
that it was an ambush.
What do you mean?
First, stab the lower back from behind.
The person turns around,
and then...
Walk forward.
One stab.
Turn around.
Right here.
One stab, two stabs.
Turn a bit.
Enough.
You're obsessed, aren't you?
The judge won't listen to this.
But right now this is
the closest assumption to the truth.
All this proves is that
Hu Xudong
didn't kill in a fit of passion,
but premeditated murder.
You're just making it worse for him.
What I want to prove is
that Hu Xudong didn't kill anyone.
Get it?
The most important thing now
is reconstructing the scene.
It's like blind men feeling an elephant.
We don't have the ability
to solve the case.
Helping the police catch the killer
isn't our job.
We're lawyers.
That's not a lawyer's job!
Don't go there yet.
Hu Xudong
has no criminal record,
right?
And he's right-handed.
The killer
is very likely a left-handed person
with a prior assault conviction
who uses a short knife.
Give it a rest
with the left-right hand stuff!
You think you're Sherlock Holmes?
Come on, man.
Filing a lawsuit
isn't like writing a detective novel.
Everything has to be based on evidence.
If we had
a solid alibi,
we could fight this case.
But we don't.
Don't keep thinking that way.
Two months ago, we couldn't even
see the case files.
What kind of situation is this now?
Now
the amendment
to the Criminal Procedure Law
is an opportunity for Hu Xudong.
We have to seize it for him.
I'm not as optimistic as you.
Right now,
our right to review files is limited.
Lin Huaimin has been decent to you,
hasn't obstructed things.
But you still can't
verify the physical evidence.
I'll leave my words here.
There will definitely
be new testimony and evidence
at trial.
What about us?
We've got nothing but
logical reasoning
and subjective speculation.
Are you that pessimistic?
Yes.
I'm an optimistic
pessimist.
I always have been.
Otherwise, why wouldn't I
do criminal defense?
So you think
there's no hope for me to plead
not guilty for him?
Slim.
Just let the court decide.
If they don't find him guilty,
they won't even hold a trial.
You should be well aware of that.
So according to you,
we should just stop trying.
What's the point?
If everyone thinks like this,
we should just quit.
Why investigate at all?
Just get his old friend Wang Benshan
to defend him.
First-time offender, incidental offender,
with good attitude in pleading guilty,
requesting a lighter sentence.
That's it.
Why bother?
What are we investigating every day for?
Isn't it all for advancement?
I've booked my ticket.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Ding Rui is about to give birth.
Premature.
Here, take this.
It'll come in handy later.
I don't need it.
Take it!
Put it on the table.
[Binjiang Intermediate People's Court]
[Deputy Court President's Office]
That case in Dashijia Village—
you told the Court Pres.
to put me on it?
The higher-ups take it very seriously.
I also told Court Pres. Qiu
that I want to preside over
the trial myself.
I've been
following the case for a long time.
It's quite interesting.
If it weren't for
Qian Xingliang's matter,
you'd have been promoted long ago.
This is your chance.
There's one thing,
the police came to me after the incident.
Did you give a statement
or sign anything?
No, just an informal chat.
Then it doesn't matter.
You're not a witness either.
Besides, the defendant's defense lawyer
is Chen Yizhong.
Did you know that?
Yeah, I know. What's wrong?
I shouldn't be involved in this case.
Why?
Are you married?
No.
Are you dating?
We were all classmates.
I was classmates with Yizhong too.
There are plenty of lawyers
and prosecutors who were classmates.
So what?
Just because we know each other,
we can't have professional dealings?
You think putting me
on this case
is doing me a favor?
It's not about favors.
It's just work.
I request to recuse myself.
I know you want to take it.
I don't.
I mean, I can't be involved in this.
Do you want to or not?
Who's this gorgeous one
in the mirror?
Did you draw that?
Run.
It's Sun and his crew
bringing the chickens.
I... I'll get the door.
I'll draw a little kitty for you.
A little kitty.
Meow, meow.
I'll draw it for you later.
Coming right up.
Coming.
You—
You're here.
Alright.
What's wrong?
You gave up so easily.
I'm innocent.
You'd confess too if you were me.
Why didn't you tell me?
Everything's fine now, isn't it?
No, it's not.
Alright. It's fine.
Alright.
Let go now.
I'm doing fine.
No, you're not.
Next week,
he'll have his second round of chemo.
The doctor said
his condition is stable for now.
It must be hard on you.
Why did you two hide it from me?
Ask him.
First he said
he didn't want to distract you from work.
Then he said
you just got married
and he shouldn't bother you.
He also said
he was afraid you'd worry too much
about Yan Jicai's case.
And now—
he says after this chemo,
he's going back to Bieshan.
Well, I have to go back
and hand things over
properly anyway.
I...
hid it from you.
I was wrong.
I... I apologize.
You always know you're wrong
and apologize.
But in the end?
You do exactly
what you were going to do anyway.
Exactly.
See? That's what
a good education gets you.
You summed him up
in one sentence.
My main worry is that Lihui's
still fixated
on Yan Jicai's case.
If she finds out I'm sick,
s-she'd definitely
not be able to sit still.
We sent an official letter
to the Nanlu Procuratorate.
No response yet.
Looks like there's a lot of resistance.
There sure is.
Now that I'm at the Nanlu Procuratorate,
and with my relationship with Jianmin,
I feel like my hands are tied.
I'm going to put it aside for now.
That's right.
You should put it aside.
Look, you're still young.
You can't sacrifice your
career and life for it,
right?
You shouldn't feel guilty.
Besides,
you've got me.
You're sick.
I'm in good health.
I'm fine.
I walk 10,000 steps a day.
Alright.
Alright. This is enough.
What?
It's getting late.
You should get some rest.
I'll take Lihui to the guesthouse.
We'll come back tomorrow.
You—
Prosecutor You,
I want to stay with my mentor
for a while longer.
Your luggage is still in my car.
Let's go.
Go now.
Prosecutor You.
Is something wrong?
A message came from the prison.
Yan Jicai committed suicide.
Let's go.
Here, have some water.
Thank you.
When did you first
meet Hu Xudong?
We grew up together.
Has his temper
always been like this?
He definitely has a terrible temper.
But if you say he killed someone,
I don't believe it.
He's all bark, no bite.
No real guts.
But he has a kind heart.
What makes you say that?
He lived next door
to that Yin Ping, right?
He's been helping
his grandmother with chores
for years.
And what did he get for it?
Got blamed by everyone.
Tell me about it.
Yin Ping had an uncle.
Right?
Don't even mention that bastard.
When his mother was alive,
he was nowhere to be found.
Now that she's dead,
he comes back for compensation.
Is he even human?
That day you drank with Hu Xudong,
how late did you drink until?
The cops have asked me that several times.
I really can't remember.
I drank too much.
After you two
finished drinking, was the light on
when he left?
Light?
Yeah, I think.
Off you go.
You should get some rest too.
Clean this up.
Go.
Happy wedding, buddy.
Anyway, I fell asleep after he left.
I got up to pee
in the middle of the night.
I don't know what happened to the light.
It just wouldn't turn on.
How long did you sleep in between?
Do you have any idea?
I really can't recall.
Around 3 a.m.,
while everyone else was asleep,
he tied his pant leg
to the upper bunk rail.
Fortunately,
his cellmates were vigilant
and saved him.
Then he bit his tongue.
So many people would be implicated.
Yan Jicai,
do you think
since I was transferred
and Prosecutor Guo is away,
no one will care about your case?
Is that it?
[Cancer]
We've been keeping it secret.
Who told him?
Yes.
Prosecutor Guo isn't
doing well right now,
but he's actively
cooperating with treatment.
I came back specifically for this.
By the way, I'll show you something.
I took it a month ago.
Lie down.
Yan Jicai,
even if we can't overturn your conviction,
as long as you behave
and work toward a sentence commutation,
by the time you get out,
you can still see her
graduate from college.
Think about what you should do.
I have more
worthwhile things to do.
This is my last time reminding you.
It's up to you.
Lie down.
Lie down. Lie still.
I'll leave the photo with you.
Whether to give it to him and when,
you decide.
How's your mentor?
I believe
God won't be so heartless.
Got everything. Let's go.
Sir.
Well,
lately,
anything new found?
Yeah.
What is it?
The cigarettes your buddy
gave me last time were fake.
[Lawyer Chen, the court
wants me to hear this case.]
Yu Gaoyuan asked you
to join the case?
I've known him for so many years,
but I still don't understand him.
You're not the only one.
Who understands him?
I used to think he was just
a bit insecure,
a bit proud,
a bit power-hungry,
and a bit jealous.
Now he's getting
more and more complicated.
But it's easy for him
to see through me.
He's right.
Honestly,
I really do
want to take this case,
even though I know
there's not much I can do.
Who would have thought that
the few of us from Nanyu
would almost all gather
on this one case?
Exactly.
Just missing Lihui now.
So we have to work hard.
Let's not let Lihui down again.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
What happened to your face?
I... I just handled a
difficult case,
and solved it.
Have a seat.
Okay.
Mr. Qin,
you
always go all out every time.
It makes me
both worried and happy.
I understand why you're worried.
But why are you happy?
I'm happy because
I found the right person.
I...
I'm already married.
My kid is pretty grown up now.
You...
You're really good at joking.
I'm not looking for a husband.
I'm looking for a partner.
Our company's
business in Nanlu
is getting bigger and bigger.
We need to hire a legal advisor.
We applied to the boss,
and he approved it.
You
are the most suitable candidate.
Legal advisor?
May I know
how much your annual salary is here,
roughly?
You don't have to say
if you don't want to.
Well,
I'm a partner in the firm.
I have a base salary,
commissions, year-end bonus,
and dividends—
Alright.
How about this, Mr. Qin?
Our company can offer you
15,000 yuan a month,
plus a double-year-end bonus.
All in all,
it's about over 200,000 a year.
What do you think?
But
you have to work in Nanlu.
Our company is there.
Also,
you have to rent your own place.
About this,
I have to discuss it
with my partner.
Sure.
Think about it
and get back to me as soon as possible.
Okay.
Wait for me.
Let me go get changed,
and we'll go have dinner together.
Okay.
Come on, drink more of it.
-Okay.
-Here.
Okay.
Cheers.
Where did you go drinking?
And with whom?
Which tramp were you with this time?
I stewed black chicken and cooked dishes
at home waiting for you,
and you went out
living it up with someone else!
What are you trying to do?
Svoboda.
What does that mean?
What do you mean?
Svoboda.
Tell me, what have I ever asked of you?
Just that you'd
live a good life with me.
Have I ever been disloyal to you?
I may have a bad temper,
but I've always taken care of you
and this family.
Tell me, what else do you want?
What else do you want?
Svoboda.
[Gui Xiaotang, General Manager
of Guangdong Dingji Trading Group]
It's not that I don't support you.
I'm just advising you to be cautious.
If you want to get things done,
you better keep a low profile.
If you can't get it done
with a low profile,
a high profile
will only make things worse.
But I can't think of
any other way.
Let's not think about
anything else for now.
Provincial media, city media—
which outlet would dare publish it?
What about going higher up?
Have you thought about the consequences?
Prosecutor You gave this to me.
My mentor's medal.
I want him to wear it on his chest
while he's alive,
not have it pressed under the Party flag
after he's gone.
I don't want him to leave with regrets.
If it really gets reported,
there will be many possibilities.
It could turn out very badly,
or nothing might happen at all.
The wrongful conviction
could be overturned,
or the original verdict could stand.
Worst case...
Worst case, the original verdict stands,
and I resign.
Lihui,
we've really done our best.
To be honest,
going all out like this
for Yan Jicai—
the cost is too high.
I'm not just doing this for Yan Jicai.
It's also for justice under the law,
for my mentor,
and for Yan Jicai's wife
and daughter.